>> 凯尔: 那么你会思考，好吧，如果我能输入一个变量，
&gt;&gt; Kyle: So then you get to thinking,
well, if i can put a variable,
如果我能把一个表情放在括号里
if i can put an expression
inside of those parentheses and
那就立即进行那个表情，为什么我不能
then immediately run that expression,
why couldn't i just
把另一个老师的功能放在一个表情上 ?
take the another teacher function and
put it as an expression?
为什么我要将其转换为变量并将其放入变量中 ?
Why do I have to make it into
a variable and put the variable in?
我为什么不把那个功能放在那里
Why don't I just take that function and
put it right there?
因此，我们将用函数表达式替换变量。
So here we're going to replace
the variable with the function expression.
在第一套括号里
Now inside of that first
set of parentheses,
我们还有第二套括号来执行它
we still have the second set of
parentheses down here to execute it.
我们有一个函数表达式，然后立即调用。
We have a function expression
that is then immediately invoked.
作为我们在 JavaScript中非常有创意的人
And being the terribly creative
bunch that we are in JavaScript,
在 2010 年我们创造了一个词组立即调用函数表达式
back in 2010 we coined the phrase
immediately invoked function expression,
a.b.a
a.k.a IIFE.
这就是它的来源
That's where this comes from,
使用函数表达式创建作用域，立即调用它。
using a function expression to create
a scope, immediately invoking it.
它是一种短暂的东西，我们只需要它的时候，就这样
It's a sort of ephemeral thing,
we only need it for that moment, just so
我们可以有一个范围
we can have a scope.
这样它就会运行一次然后它就会消失
So it runs once and
then it kinda goes away.
它不像一个常规的功能，我们可能需要多次调用。
It's not like a regular function that
we might need to call multiple times.
这是一次和做过的事情，这就是为什么我们使用 IIF 模式。
It's a once and done sort of thing, and
that's why we use the IIFE pattern.
为什么这不是函数声明?
Why is this not a function declaration?
>> 扬声器 2: 一些括号。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Some sort of parentheses.
>> 凯尔: 因为单词函数不是语句中的第一个。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Because the word function is
not the first thing in the statement.
换句话说，这些括号实际上是没有其他目的的。
In other words, those parentheses
are there literally for no other purpose
而不是把它变成表情而不是声明
than to syntactically turn that into
an expression instead of a declaration.
有多种其他语法方法可将函数转换为
There are a variety of other syntactic
ways to turn a function into
一个表情。
an expression.
例如，而不是第一个周围的括号集合，
For example, instead of the first
surrounding parentheses set,
我们可以让一个一元运算符，比如一个加号，一个或一个减号，或者一个波浪号。
we could have put a unary operator, like
a plus or a negate or a minus or a tilde.
我们本来可以用最出名但还是很重要的
We could have even used the lesser
known but still important delete or
无效运算符。
void operators.
那些一元运算符中的任何一个都将会产生从
Anyone of those unary operators would
have had the effect of turning that from
函数声明到函数表达式中，以及
a function declaration into
a function expression, and
它就能执行了
it would have then been able to execute.
我们不需要这样如果我们能在概念上
We'd like to not have to, it would be
nice if we could conceptually just
执行函数声明，然后再考虑它，
make a function declaration that executes,
but then think about it,
即使我们能做到这一点，功能声明仍然会产生
even if we could do that, the function
declaration would still have the effect of
污染封闭范围。
polluting the enclosing scope.
所以我们真正需要的是一个我们能运行的功能
So what we really need here is
a function that we can run, and
不污染封闭范围。
not pollute the enclosing scope.
通过将其转化为函数表达式，我们就能做到这一点。
And by turning it into a function
expression, we accomplish that.
所以另一个老师的名字也没出现
So the name another
teacher doesn't show up.
现在你几乎可以肯定你的 IIFEs 是匿名的了
Now you've almost certainly
seen your IIFEs as anonymous.
你几乎可以看到那些没有名字的 IIFEs
You've almost certainly seen those IIFEs
without any name there, like you see here
在第 4 行，因为我们的爱与匿名函数的表达。
on line 4, because of our love affair
with anonymous function expressions.
我之前的建议是什么
Recall my recommendation from earlier?
永远不要你有匿名的功能
Never, ever, ever should you have
anonymous function expressions, and
包括您的 IFFIEs。
that includes your IFFIEs.
如果你做的是 IIF ，有一定的目的。
If you are making an IIFE,
there's some purpose for it.
在我这愚蠢的例子里我们说的是一个老师
In my silly example here where
we're talking about a teacher,
没那么多的目的
there's not a lot of purpose.
这不是很容易弄明白的。
It's not very easy to figure out.
你还可以叫它另一个老师
You could still call it another teacher or
请提供其他名称来描述该特定作用域的用途。
give it some other name to describe
the purpose of that particular scope.
>> 凯尔: 如果你真的被卡住了，你不能有任何名字
&gt;&gt; Kyle: And if you really are just stuck
and you can't come up with any name
来描述某些特定范围的需求。
to describe the need for
some particular scope.
>> 凯尔: 那就用 " IIFE" 这个词。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Then just use the word IIFE.
IIFE ，大写字母。
IIFE, in capital letters.
它就会出现在你的堆里
And it's gonna show up
in your stack trace,
你就会知道它是从 IIF来的
you're gonna know it's
coming from an IIFE.
那还不如去看匿名的功能
That's still better than seeing
an anonymous function, and
不知道它是从哪里来的，也不知道它是为了什么。
having no idea where it came from,
or what it was for.
>> 凯尔: 这些 IIFEs 有什么好的，不管他们是匿名的，
&gt;&gt; Kyle: What's nice about these IIFEs,
whether they're anonymous or not,
就是它们只是功能，意味着我们可以传递价值。
is that they are just functions,
which means we can pass in values.
所以在这里，我可以消除，甚至不需要做任何任务。
So here, I was able to eliminate,
didn't even need to make any assignments.
我只能将一个值传递给一个参数。
I can just pass in a value to a parameter.
>> 凯尔: 顺便说一下， IIFE 的另一个用法可能有点不太普通，但是
&gt;&gt; Kyle: By the way, another usage for
IIFE, it may be a little less common, but
IIFE 的另一个用法是将语句转换为
another usage for IIFE is for
turning things that are statements into
表达式，因为和 IIFE 是表达式。
expressions, because and
IIFE is an expression.
有时候会有方便的地方
There are sometimes places where
it would be convenient to have
语句处于表达式位置。
a statement be in an expression position.
其中一个例子，我曾多次参加，
One of those examples,
which I have run into on many occasions,
我想把一个任务分配给一个变量
is I would like to be able to make
an assignment to a variable and
然后，分配表达式包含 try， catch。
then have that assignment
expression include a try, catch.
比如说我经常做老师等于fetch老师和
For example, I often will do something
like teacher equals fetchteacher and
该函数可能抛出异常。
that function might be
able to throw exception.
所以如果我能把它裹在一个尝试的渔获上，那就好了。
So it would be nice if I would wrap that
in a try catch then have a fall back.
下面是尝试捕捉的是一个声明
Well, the down side is the try
catch is a statement so
它在一个表达位置上不起作用。
it doesn't work in an expression position.
那是我们语法的一个不幸的细微差别
That's an unfortunate
nuance of our grammar.
下一个最好的东西就是我们只做一个变量
And so the next best hack is
that we just make a variable and
然后再分配两次就像我们在这里一样
then assign to it twice,
like we're doing here.
很多人可能会这样做，我当然也会这样做。
And a lot of you probably do this,
and I certainly have as well.
但我希望能让它变得更清晰
But I would like to be able to make it
clearer especially if there was gonna be
比三到四个多的代码行
more lines of code than just the three or
four.
我想让读者明白我的代码
I'd like to make it clear
to the reader of my code,
老师只会被安排一次
that teacher only gets assigned once.
这不是很明显的代码
That's not terribly
obvious from this code.
你得想办法，好吧，我只得到两个值中的一个。
You have to sort of figure out, okay,
I'm only getting one of the two values.
我想说的是，老师被分配了一次。
And I'd like to make it obvious
that teacher gets assigned once.
所以如果我使用 IIF
So, if I use an IIFE,
我可以更清楚的完成一点，我可以做一个 try catch 语句
I can accomplish that a little bit more
clearly, I can make a try catch statement
通过将函数表达式环绕在表达式中。
into an expression by wrapping
a function expression around it.
不是很普通但我只是在说 IIFEs 可以用你的任何地方
Not very common, but I'm just pointing out
that IIFEs can be used any place that you
需要一个表达式，并且任何时候都需要一个语句或
need an expression, and
any time you need a statement or
作用域在表达式位置， IIFE 完成该任务。
a scope in an expression position,
the IIFE accomplishes that task.